

# Manuel Smith Technical Writer

In need of a technical writer that explains abstract concepts eloquently such that even the most technically-inexperienced reader can understand? Look no further!

I write technical and marketing content optimized for human readers and search engine crawlers.

Extensive keyword research is the core of my content strategy.

Let's discuss if I sound like a great fit.

#### HARD SKILLS

- Google Docs, Sheets and Slides
- Networking Subnetting & Routing
- Virtualization
- · Admin-level Linux and CLI
- Python, NodeJS (Express) and C++
- HTML CSS and JavaScript(React)
- Fetch API (JSON) and XMLHttpRequest
- Git and GitHub
- Grammarly
- UML Diagramming
- UX-Writing
- Photoshop and Canva

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Technical Writer & Editor SKUDONET | Sept-2023 - Now

- Enhanced and updated extensive documentation for Skudonet's products, ensuring accuracy and clarity.
- Produced engaging video content to promote Skudonet's offerings, effectively communicating key features and benefits.
- Played a vital role in maintaining a consistent brand image through content and video materials.
- Monitored and analyzed content performance metrics to refine strategies and maximize impact.

# Technical Writer & Editor

# ZEVENET | July-2022 - Sept-2023

- Developed and Edited UX-friendly Technical documentation, drastically reducing bounce rate
- Conducted Market research to understand customer needs and used that information to craft well-targeted how-to guides with the help of Zevenet Developers
- Conducted reviews and provided feedback on technical documents created by other team members.
- Worked closely with product managers, engineers, and other stakeholders to ensure accuracy and completeness of technical documents.

# **SOFT SKILLS**

- Research
- TeamWork
- Problem solving
- Creativity
- Emotional Intelligence
- Customer Service
- Negotiation
- Critical Thinking

### **EDUCATION**

- Degree in Information security and Technology | Utah Tech University -2019-2022
- CCNA | Cisco Ongoing

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**



#### **Technical Writer & Editor**

### CRANELUX | 2020 - now

- Created and maintained templates and style guides for technical documents.
- Created and maintained technical documentation, including user manuals, quick start guides
- Updated and maintained technical documentation to ensure accuracy and relevance.

# **CONTACTS**



linkedin.com/in/manuel-riddick-smith



riddicksmith37@gmail.com



4245 S. Riverdale Rd, UT



www.cranelux.com